Kamran Amini

Senior Software Engineer at ActiveVideo BV

High Skilled Migrant in Netherlands

Parnassusweg 999, Amsterdam 1082LZ

+31 (0) 611060215 Email: kam.cpp@gmail.com Github: github.com/kamcpp

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/kamcpp

SUMMARY

With over 14 years of professional experience in various fields of software development, I've dedicated my past few years to creating cloud-based distributed systems. While always been a key contributor to the overall architecture and design, considering requirements like security, availability, robustness, fault tolerance, etc, I have always had a strong will to be part of the development team and code some of the critical key components. Hence, backed by my academic studies in computer science, I have had the pleasure of learning by coding and seeing serious corner cases and bugs in action. I have used many programming languages, but system languages like C, C++, Golang, and Rust have always been amongst the most loved ones. As part of my career, I have always tried to keep an eye on the DevOps side of things, therefore, I have gained invaluable experience in scripting and configuring Bash, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, AWS resources, etc. I do love start-ups and the mindset around raising one, so Javascript and NodeJS technology is among the game-changers in that field and I've had the chance to use it extensively in different projects. Moreover, during the past few years, I have gathered a deep understanding of distributed ledgers and blockchains, so I have worked with various blockchain startups to develop their on-chain complex financial logic (smart contracts) using Solidity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Expert Level PLs: C++14 (g++, clang++) C11 (gcc, clang) Java (openJDK, Oracle) Python
- Medium Level PLs: Go Scala Erlang x86-64 Assembly
- Web: HTTP HTTPS DNS Apache httpd NGINX CGI (PHP, Python, Perl) Java Servlets (Wildfly, Jetty, Tomcat, Glassfish) Event Loops (1ibuv, Java NIO)- Spring MVC and Spring Boot Akka HTTP
- Concurrency: Multithreading Multiprocessing Event Driven Dev. (libuv, Java NIO, Netty) Actor Model (akka) Process and thread synchronization (mutexes, semaphores, condition variables, spin locks, re-entrant locks) shared memory pipes
- **Debugging:** gdb Valgrind (memcheck, massif, callgrind, helgrind, cachegrind) Clang ASAN & TSAN JConsole PDB objdump, nm, readelf
- Data Stores: PostgreSQL MySQL MongoDB Memcached Redis Zookeeper HBase Cassandra
- SCMs: Git Perforce Mercurial Subversion TFS
- Build Systems: Makefile CMake Ninja Maven Bazel sbt
- DevOps Skills: Bash Scripting Perl Python Virtualization Docker Jenkins Zabbix Netdata
- Distributed/Enterprise Systems: MQM Microservices DFS (HDFS, Luster, Gluster) Dist. Processing (Ignite, MapReduce) Dist. Caching Dist. Key-Value Stores Dist. Configuration Streaming Micro-batching CQRS Event Sourcing FT and HA DMQ (Kafka)
- Computer Science: Balanced Trees (AVL, B-Tree, RB) Graphs Index Trees Tries Sort & Search Algs Compression Algs Bit Matching Algs Time and Space complexities
- Serialization & RPC: Protobuf gRPC ZeroMQ Thrift JSON over REST SOAP Java RMI XMLRPC
- Standards: SUS and POSIX PKCS standards JavaEE (JPA, JSM, EJB, Java Servlets, JAX-WS, JAX-RS, etc) RFCs (ASN.1, IP, TCP, UDP, DNS, HTTP, CMS, etc)
- Cryptography: OpenSSL Symmetric Algs (DES, 3DES, AES) Asymmetric Algs (RSA, ECC, DH) SSL PKI (CA, Digital Signature, PKCS certs, HSMs and Cyrpto. Tokens) Wrap Keys Key Derivation Algorithms Hash Algs MAC Algs Error Detection (Crypto. Hashes)
- Computer Networks: OSI & Internet Protocol Suite, Packet Switching, Error Detection & Correction (Checksum, CRC, ARQ, FEC), L3 protocols (ICMP, IP) L4 protocols (UDP, TCP) Socket Programming L3 programming (libpcap, JNetPcap) Wireshark analysis Penetration Testing tcpdump
- Kernel Development: Linux Modules Linux System Calls
- Machine Learning: CUDA Dev. Tensorflow (C++ & Python) OpenCV (C, C++, Python) Supervised & Unsupervised Learning Reinforced Learning Deep Learning Locality Sensitive Hashes Iris Code Gabor filter Feature Selection & Extraction
- Scrum: JIRA Fisheye Confluence Bitbucket Stash Redmine GitLab -Code Reviews Pull Requests Release Chain

CAREER

★ TomTom

Senior Software Engineer (Sept. 2017 - Dec. 2018)

Netherlands, Amsterdam

- Expert Software Consultant from Modis B.V.
- NavKit Free Text Search Engine, Navkit Worker REST Services, POI Info Services
- C++11 (g++, clang) Java SE JUnit Spring MVC JAXB Spring REST gdb Valgrind Clang ASAN & TSAN STL & Boost Google Test Protobuf Thrift Python Jenkins QuickBuild Docker- JIRA Fisheye Confluence Bitbucket Stash AWS/Azure based cloud

★ Jeppesen Systems (Boeing)

Senior Software Engineer (Feb. 2017 - Aug. 2017)

Sweden, Gothenburg

- Manpower Application
 C++ (g++) Python C#.NET gdb Valgrind (callgrind, massif) PDB STL & Boost Google Test XMLRPC Jenkins JIRA -Fisheye - Confluence

★ Sahab Pardaz Co.

Deep Learning Research Developer, Enterprise Software Architect (Jul. 2016 - Jan. 2017)

Distributed Systems Architect, Senior Software Engineer (Feb. 2015 - Jun. 2015)

Iran, Tehran

- DL based Network Traffic Analyzer Network Anomaly Detector Distributed Job Coordinator
- C++ (g++) C (gcc, CUDA) Java SE Python gdb Valgrind STL & Boost Google Test Protobuf gRPC Tensorflow Zookeeper Memcached Jenkins Zabbix Redmine GitLab Github

★ Adro Co.

Senior Software Architect, Principal C++ Engineer textsl(Jun. 2016 - Jan. 2017)

Iran, Tehran

- Realtime Bidding (RTB) Engine
- C++ (g++) Python gdb Valgrind STL & Boost libuv Google Test Protobuf Jenkins Travis CI Docker JIRA Fisheye

★ Naeem Co.

Chief Technical Officer, Chief Software Architect (Apr. 2015 - Oct. 2016)

Iran, Tehran

- Projects: ePassport Issuance System Face Recognition System, Biometric Identification Sys.
- Crypto.: OpenSSL PKCS (1, 7, 10, 11, 12) ICAO MRTD standards HSM Key Mgmt. PKCS11 Tokens
- Stack: C (gcc) C++ (g++) Java SE Java EE Spring MVC Wildfly Tomcat Python gdb Valgrind STL & Boost wxWdigets
- Qt Google Test Jenkins Docker vSphere Proxmox Gluster Cassandra Redmine GitLab

★ Sharif CERT Center

Software Engineer (Dec. 2011 - Jun. 2013)

Iran, Tehran

- Botnet Detection System Sinkhole DDNS as a FreeBSD module
- C++ (g++) Java SE Perl gdb JConsole Valgrind STL & Boost Swing Redmine

FREELANCING CAREER

I have a single-person company (ZZP Bedriff) registered in Netherlands. On a casual basis, I do the following as a freelancer in my free times:

• Authoring books and articles:

The book **Extreme C** which is going to be published by **PacktPub** soon.

• Open Source Development:

Netdata: Real-time performance monitoring engine written mainly in C [github.com/netdata/netdata]

Hottentot: A light-weight serialization and RPC framework for C++ and Java [github.com/labcrypto/hottentot]

Fence: A durable queue with a centralized master node with C++, Java, and Python clients [github.com/labcrypto/fence]

Avicenna: A light-weight Dependency Injector for Java [github.com/kamcpp/avicenna]

- Software Development
- Software Design Consultancy
- Instruction and Lecturing

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Persian (Native), English (Fluent), French (Beginner), Dutch (Beginner)

EDUCATION

• 2017 - Present

The Open University

Bachelor of Science in Physics (Astronomy and Planetary Science)

• 2004 - 2008

University of Isfahan

Isfahan, Iran

Bachelor of Software Engineering

INTERESTS

- **Physics and Astronomty**: Consmology, Astronomy, Quantum Physics, Quantum Mechanics, Particle Physics, Special and General Relativity, Theory of Everything, Photonics.
- Mathematics: Linear and Abstract Algebra, Probability Theory, Information Theory
- Cryptography: Information Security, Network Security, Security Algorithms, Quantum Information Theory, Quantum Key Distribution, Quantum Cryptography
- Philosophy: Western Philosophy, Sociology, Economics, Politics and Humanities
- Telecommunications: Modulation, Multiplexing, Codes, Telecommunication circuits, Photonics and optical fibers, IEEE 802.3 Protocols, Information Theory, Coding Theory, Computer Networks, etc
- Music and Musicology: Classic, Extreme Metal, Alternative Metal, Progressive Metal, Alternative Rock, etc